他一定是在我刚才消磁时进来的
He must have pulled open the door just as I de-magnetised it.
他的头被什么东西撞了
He's got a terrible bump on his head.
哦，没什么，一点新鲜空气就能治好
Oh, nothing that a little fresh air won't cure.
我来看看外面发生什么了
I'll see what's going on outside.
嘿，警察，拦住他
'Hey, police! Hey, stop 'em!
他们要逃跑
'They're getting away!'
带着他走吧
He'll just have to come with us,that's all.
嘿，警察！
Hey, police!
刚才发生了什么？
What's going on here then?
有人抢劫珠宝店！哎，这里总是这样
Cor, what another one?It's always happening round here.
金狮电影公司出品
翻译：探discovery索
达莱克斯入侵地球——公元2150年
校对：Pindaer
本地化:RealShark
二次校对：NO MORE
后期制作：NO MORE
压制：NO MORE
这里有强盗
'Ere the robbers!
-可以用下你的电话吗？ -你叫什么名字，年轻人
- Can I use your telephone?- What is your name, young man?
Tom Campbell.K区特别警察
Tom Campbell.Special Constabulary K. Division.
-好的，今天是几号 -几号？
- Yes, and can you tell me the date?
- The date?
哦，看看我是不是还正常是三月三十一日吧
Oh, I see, you want to know if I'm all right.Yes, it's March 31st.
好了，现在我能用一下你的电话了吧
Now, can I use your telephone?
我们要到了，爷爷
We're arriving, Grandfather.
哦，很好
Oh, good.
很抱歉，我想你不能用电话，首先，我们没有
I'm afraid, you can't use the telephone.For one thing we haven't got one.
即使我们有电话，我觉得它也没什么用
And even if we had,I don't think it would do any good.
在公元2150年没有用
Not in 2150 A.D.
-2150年？ -对
- 2150? - That's right.
请允许我介绍自己
Allow me to introduce myself.
我是博士
I am Dr Who,
这是我外甥女Louise，这是我孙女Susan
this is my niece Louise and my granddaughter Susan.
还有，这是我的时光机，TARDIS
And this is my time and space machine, TARDIS.
它能带我们去任何地点，任何时间
It is capable of taking us to any age on any planet in any universe.
我们正要去现在的伦敦，时间是......
You arrived just as we were about to leave for London in the year..
.
是的，我知道，是2150年
Yes, I know, 2150.
你应该不知道这里出了一桩严重的犯罪事件吧
You don't seem to realise,there's been a serious crime committed.
我不知道你在干什么，我现在得报告你们的情况
I don't know what you're all up to.I ought to report you for this.
见鬼，2150年
2150!
为什么全都变样了
It's all different!
我告诉你了，要相信他
Well, I told you to believe him.
-但这是大白天啊 -你确定这是2150年？
- But it's daytime. - Are you sure it's 2150?
当然，我确定
Yes, quite sure, Susie.
但是爷爷，这里看起来好荒凉啊
But Grandfather, it looks so deserted.
我该说——腐烂
I should say decaying.
-好吧，伦敦发生了什么？ -今天是星期日吧
- Well, what's happened to London then?- Maybe it's Sunday.
不可能，星期日我该踢足球的
Of course it's not Sunday.I'm playing football Sunday!
来吧，Louise，看看这边来
Come on, Louise,let's investigate over here.
这没有机器，没有声音
No machines, no voices.
甚至没有鸟
And there aren't any birds!
哦，我脑袋被那玩意打乱了
That bloke must have hit me harder than I thought.
Susan!
快来！
Come here!
小心！
Look out!
谢谢你，当心点
Thank you, my boy.
看！
Look!
-我们不可能搬得动 -那边有个仓库
- We'll never shift this lot.- There's a warehouse over there.
我们去看看能不能找到点什么东西
Let's see if we can find a crowbar or something.
-我想我扭到脚了 -哦，Susan
- I think I've hurt my ankle.- Oh, Susie.
哦，你最好和Louise呆在这里
You'd better stay here with Louise.
来吧，年轻人，别站在那里了
Come along, young man,don't stand there dithering.
博士，我不懂，为什么时间向前了那么多
Look, Doc, I don't understand this at all,all this moving forward in time.
还有那个东西
And what about the inside of that thing?
它在外面很普通，里面却像座房子
Well, on the outside it's ordinary enough,but inside it's the size of a house.
啊，年轻人，我喜欢好奇的头脑
Ah, my boy,I like an enquiring mind.
正如，时间是第四维
Just as time is regarded as the fourth dimension,
那么，空间就是第五维
so space is equally the fifth dimension.
因为空间是无边界的，是没有时间概念的
For space knows no boundaries and is completely timeless.
我想这样解释已经很清楚了
There. I'm sure that's made it perfectly clear, eh?
哦，这完全清楚了，呃...
Oh, yeah, perfectly clear... to me.
还有一个问题要问你，博士...
There is another question I'd like to put to you, Doctor.
呃？博士你在哪？哦，这里
Doctor? Where are you? Oh, there you are.
-恩，如果你能去任何地方，那么... -嘘
- Look, if you can travel anywhere... - Shh...
看看这里
Try around here.
Susan?
Susan!
别出声，我就让你走
No noise, and I'll let you go.
-Susan呢？你把她弄到哪里去了 -她没事
- What have you done with Susan?- The kid's all right.
你真蠢，怎么可以这样在外面乱跑
You must be stupid moving about in the open like this.
-我们去哪？-你想看到那个小女孩，不是吗？
- Where are we going? - You want to see the girl, don't you?
-是的，但是... -跟我来
- Yes, but...- Well, come on then.
他死了
He's dead.
博士，看，通话机
Doctor, the radio.
这肯定是一个接收器之类的
Certainly a receiver of some sort.
哦，这是非常先进的微型天线
Oh, it's highly advanced -miniature antennae.
有枪声
Gunfire!
我们回去看看
Let's get back.
可能是凶手
That could be the killer.
咱们好好搜查一下吧
Well, we'd better investigate.
快来
Come on.
博士，拉我一把
Doc, give me...
快，拉我进去
Pull me in.
谢谢你，博士
Thank you, Doctor.
我看不到女孩子了，她们去哪里了
I can't see the girls anywhere.Where have they gone?
快走
Come on!
-真壮观 -像是一个飞碟
- Quite remarkable.- It's a flying saucer!
是的，用这个词很恰当
Yes, that's a very apt description.
恩，它好像在斯隆广场降落了
Well, it appears to be landing in the vicinity of Sloane Square.
来吧，博士，让我们找到她们然后离开这里
Come on, Doc,let's find the girls and get out of here.
Louise!
-哦，太好了，你没事 -来吧，别停下来
- Oh, thank heavens you're all right.- Come on, keep moving.
-那他们怎么办？ -他们？
- What about the others?- What others?
我爷爷，还有一个叫Tom的警察
My grandfather and a policeman called Tom.
回头我去找，快走
I'll go back for them later.Come on.
-有什么线索吗？-没有
- Any sign of them? - No.
我们到那边看看
Let's try over here.
-我们快到了 -Wyler！
- We're nearly there.- Wyler.
-她们两个是谁？ -我在河边发现的她们
- Who are these two?- I found them down by the river
.
我在仓库那里差点被抓走
I was nearly caught at the warehouse.
看见了一个老头和一个年轻人
There were two of them -an old man and a young man.
那是我爷爷和Tom！
That must have been my grandfather and Tom.
那些机器人知道那仓库
The Robomen know about the warehouse.
-你肯定吗 -我杀了一个要抓我的机器人
- Are you sure?- There was a Roboman waiting for me.
然后又来了两个人
Then these other two arrived.
我不知道他们是谁，所以我就从后门出来了
I didn't know who they were，so I came out the back way.
求你找到我爷爷
Please get my grandfather.
-我试试吧 -不行！这样太危险了
- I'll try.- No! It's too dangerous.
-没关系 -谢谢
- I'll try.- Thanks.
这是Susan的，它是湿的
This is Susan's.It's wet.
Louise用这个给她洗的脚踝
Perhaps Louise was bathing her ankle.
-是啊，她们也许在河边 -恩
- Yeah. They might be down by the river.- Yes.
Susan!
注意身后!
Behind you!
Dalek!
Daleks!
把囚犯带到飞船上去！
Take the prisoners to the space ship.
快！
Move!
在河边抓到逃犯
Intercept escaping human in river area.
-Wyler他们是新来的? -河边碰到的
- New recruits, Wyler?-- I picked them up near the river.
从船上下来的？先到海边去
Came down on a boat, eh?Trying for the coast.
可是你们到不了伦敦了，呃
But you couldn't get through to London, eh?
好的，你们可能有点用，在这里很安全
Well, we can use you -you'll be safe here.
注意！注意！
Attention! Attention!
伦敦的幸存者！注意！
'Survivors of London,
Dalek是地球的主人！
'the Daleks are the masters of Earth.'
Daleks?
The Daleks?
立即投降，才会活下来
'Surrender now and you will live.
如果反抗，你将被消灭!
'Resist and you will be exterminated.
立即在街上集合！
'Show yourselves in the streets immediately
服从你们主人Dalek的命令！
'and obey the orders of your masters, the Daleks!'
叫我们服从那些机器垃圾桶？走着瞧！
Obey motorised dustbins!We'll see about that.
好！把这些枪上好油！
Good. Keep that gun well oiled!
叫它们看看谁才是这的主人！叫它们看看！
We'll show them who the masters are!We'll show them.
嘿！怎么了？
Hey, what's going on?
我们不能留在这里，我们必须走！
We can't stay here,we must go.
别干傻事，你们不能走！你们在这里很安全！
Don't be silly, you can't go out there.You're safe here.
那外面的人怎么办？
But what about the others outside?
别替他们担心，他们会没事的
Ah, stop worrying,they're sure to be all right.
但那是我爷爷!
But it's my grandfather.
那也不行！满街都是Dalek！
Well, it's no good,the streets will be crawling with Daleks.
-怎么回事？-外面还有两个人
- What's this?- There's another two of 'em out there.
我们什么忙也帮不上，真抱歉
There's nothing we can do for them.I'm sorry.
-会发生什么事？ -谁也说不准
- What's going to happen?- No one's absolutely certain.
他们已经把整个的Bedfordshire都变成了一个巨大的矿区
They've turned the whole of Bedfordshire into a gigantic mining area.
它们要挖到地球的中心，别问我为什么
I'd say they're burrowing right down to the Earth's core, but don't ask me why.
-不等挖完它们就要炸掉这个星球 -它们休想！
- They'll blow this planet to bits.- Do you think we'll let them?
它们用陨石轰炸我们
They've bombarded us with meteorites,
用外太空射线袭击我们
subjected us to cosmic rays,smashed our cities,
毁灭我们的城市，消灭我们的整个种族
destroyed whole continents of people.
把我们中的一些人变成了植物人!
Some of us,they've turned into living dead...
机器人
Robomen.
成千上万的人都死在了矿里
Thousands of others are dying inside their mine,
但是我要告诉你，车轮转360度
but I'll tell you this, Wyler,the wheel's turning full circle.
-我们的末日来了 -也许吧
- Our day's coming!- Maybe.
我晚了一步
I was just too late.
它们两个都被俘获了，被抓上了飞碟
They were both captured and taken to one of the flying saucers.
它们会怎样？
What will they do with them?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不明白
I do not understand it.
Dalek们已经被消灭了，我亲眼看见的
The Daleks were destroyed.I was there, I saw it happen.
-什么时候？ -不知道
- When was this? - Well, I don't know.
TARDIS出乎我们的意料，它把我带到了它们的星球——Skaro
TARDIS took us by accident to the Dalek planet, Skaro,
也许是在未来吧
but perhaps that was some time in the future.
但是Dalek只能在金属上行走，它们是...
Those Daleks could only travel on metal.These are...
那个人在我巡逻时杀了另外两个人
This man killed the other two men in my patrol.
你将取代他们
Then you shall replace them.
加入其他囚犯的队伍！
Join the other prisoners.
继续巡逻！
Continue your patrol.
我们得想办法逃脱
We'll have to make a break.
-它们要是进了我们的地方就完了 -唉，没有希望
- Once they get us inside the saucer...- Ah, there isn't a hope.
真是的，看我的！
Isn't there? Watch me.
Thompson,回来！
Thompson, come back!
快回来，Thompson！你跑不了！
Come back, Thompson,you'll never make it!
Thompson!
Thompson, 看看它们
Thompson, look out they're...
小心！
Look out there!
消灭!
Exterminate!
把囚犯带到飞船去
Prisoners will proceed into the ship.
任何形式的反抗将以同样的方式处理！
Any further resistance will be dealt with in the same way.
飞碟要在地上停留多久？
How long will the saucer stay on the ground?
恩，这个
Just fix this in there... that's it.
我认为要等它们抓到足够多的囚犯
Until they've got enough prisoners to take to the mine, I suppose.
-要把他们都运去飞船吗？ -哦，当然
- Do they take them all to the mine?- Yes, of course.
我从没见过飞碟，所以我也不清楚
Well, look I've never been inside a saucer - how do I know?
它们在那里把人都变成机器了？
Is that where they robotise the prisoners?
是的
Yes.
前三个！
First three prisoners.
再三个！
Next three prisoners.
最后三名！
Forward, last three prisoners.
所有Dalek立即回到中央控制室！
All Daleks,return to Central Control immediately.
它们走了，要是它们把左边的出口匝道放下来就好了
They're going. Now, if they've only left the exit ramp down.
你觉得它们会让你走？
Do you think they're going to let you walk out?
-打开你的口袋 -可是这门怎么开呢？
- Turn out your pockets.- How are you going to get the door open?
-我想好了就告诉你 -我这有一些零钱和这只笔
- I'll show you if I can find what I want.- I've got some loose change and a pen.
-不，我需要一个绝缘体 -我这有把梳子，博士
- No, I need something non-conductive.- I've got a comb here, Doctor.
-好的，我想这玩意就可以了 -太好了,你想怎么办，博士？
- Yes, I believe that will do the trick nicely.- Well, what's the idea?
这些门都是用磁性关闭的我们只需把两极分开
These doors are closed by magnetics.All we have to do is to break the two poles.
-哦，是吗？ -是的
- Oh, is that all? - Yes.
对，这里，把梳子放在这里
Yes, here.We have to force our comb in here.
走吧
Come along.
-需要我们回去吗？ -站在原地！
- Back in the cell?- Stay where you are.
你可以逃跑，证明你符合我们的智力标准
You have passed the intelligence test by escaping.
你要拿我们怎么样？
And what are you going to do with us?
你们将被机器化！
You will be robotised.
快走！
Move.
伦敦的叛逆者这是我们的最后一次警告！
Rebels of London,this is our final warning.
离开你的藏身之处
Leave your hiding places.
立刻到街上来！
'Show yourselves in the streets.
有需要你们的工作！
'Work is needed from you,
Dalek会保证你们的生命安全！
'but the Daleks offer you life.
我们会很快毁掉伦敦！
'Soon we will destroy London completely,
那时你们都会死！
'and you will all die.
这是你们最后的机会从那里出来！
'This is your last chance to come out of your hiding places.'
我们应该出去，去战斗
We'll come out of our hiding places and fight.
我们成功了，我们成功研制炸弹了！
We can do it, Wyler,we can do it with these bombs.
我们如何靠近它们？
And how do we get near enough to throw them
-做给我看！给我看啊！-至少我们可以做出手势！
- Show me. Go on, show me!- Well, at least we can make the gesture.
-赌命？-为什么不？
- With people?- Why not?
-算了吧！-Wyler
- Forget it!- Wyler...
-已成功改造他们 -释放！
- Robotising process completed.- Release them.
你们要服从Dalek的命令！
Obey Daleks without question.
是！我们服从！
We obey without question.
去飞船上巡逻！
Patrol area near this space ship.
快进去！
Move into the compartments.
快！
Move!
准备机器化
Prepare robotising process.
停！
Halt!
我们要把囚犯带到太空船
We're taking the prisoners to the space ship.
这些俘虏来自哪里?
What sector do these prisoners come from?
从第四区
Sector 4.
第四区没有巡逻！
No patrol has been allotted to Sector 4.
警报！所有Dalek立刻到主坡斜道我们被攻击了
General alert! All Daleks to main ramp.We are under attack.
紧急情况！紧急情况!
Emergency! Emergency!
我们是不是该停止机器化？
Shall we stop the robotising?
不，继续！
No, proceed.
快！
Come on!
很好，快下来，下来
That's it. Get down.Down!
谢谢，伙计
Thanks, mate.
小心，它转过来了
Careful! Spin him around!
卡住了！
It's stuck.
快，走吧！
Never mind, leave him!
所有Dalek，返回行动！
All Robomen return into action!
消灭入侵者！
Destroy invaders!
快来！
Come on!
那女孩在哪？你看见那女孩了吗？
Where's the girl?Have you seen the girl?
看见那女孩了吗？
Listen, where's the girl?
哈
Yee-ha!
消灭入侵者
Exterminate rebels!
-这边，快走 -但是...
- This way, come on.- No, but...
快走！
No, come on!
不行，炸弹没用！
They're no good.The bombs are no good.
消灭!
Exterminate!
Dalek和机器人返回飞船！
Daleks and Robomen return to space ship.
不，我没事
No, I'm all right.
我是唯一回来的吧
I'm the only one, eh?
是的，你是第一个
Yes, you're the first.
也是最后一个
Or the last.
出了什么事
What happened?
失败了
It was a failure.
我们本打算带几个囚犯的，可是...
We managed to get one or two prisoners away, but...
我爷爷怎么样了？
What about my grandfather?
-一个老头，瘦瘦的 -对
- An oldish man, thin faced? - Yes.
应该和David在一起
I think he's with David.
你的那些炸弹根本没用，我们没有机会
Your bombs were no good.We didn't have a chance.
我们继续反抗，必须反抗
We've got to go on resisting, we must.
但是你总不能拿血和肉反抗吧
But you can't fight metal with flesh and blood.
飞船已被击穿
An attack on the Dalek space ship has been defeated.'
-我们要从这逃出去 -对
- We'll have to get away from here.- Right.
我们设法去伦敦郊区
We'll make our way to the outskirts of London.
去找辆车，那里的车多着呢
We'll pick up a van there -there's plenty of transport lying about.
然后把人们重新组织起来
Then we'll hide out in the country somewhere till we can re-group.
那我的爷爷和Louise怎么办呢？
What about my grandfather and Louise?
如果他们和David回来
Well, if they're with David they'll come back here.
给他们留个纸条
Leave a message.
嘘，没事，是我，Tom，别出声
Shh. It's all right. It's me, it's Tom.Look, don't talk.
那里有一个很好的藏身之地，来
There's a marvellous place to hide over here, come on.
在这后面
Behind this thing.
-怎么了？-你干什么了？
- What's happened now? - What have you done?
停！
Stop it.
想办法让他停下来
Try and stop it.
听着，别让它...
Look, don't let it...
试试上面的那个
Try the top one there.
快点
Come here.
打开
Lift that up.
走吧
Come on.
-你怎么在这？-我被它们困住了
- What are you doing here?- I was trapped in the raid.
我也是，虽然我看见博士逃脱了
So was I.I saw the Doctor escape though.
=他还好吗？ -我想是的
- He's all right then, is he?- I think so.
帮我脱掉这东西
Get me out of this thing, will you?
看不见Dalek了
No signs of the Daleks anyway.
Dortmun和其他人要继续前进
Dortmun and the others must have decided to move on.
-是啊，可他们到哪里了？-我不知道
- Yes, but where have they gone? - I don't know.
-你说Susan在这里，还有Louise -是啊
- Susan was here you say, and Louise?- Yes.
-你应该让她们留下来 -她们不听
- You should have made them stay.- They wouldn't listen.
-你应该让她们听你的 -那倒是
- You should have made them listen!- All right!
这也许可以猜到她们去哪了
This may give us some idea of where they've gone.
对，那是大矿区，一定是Dortmun圈的
Yes, that's the big mine area.Dortmun must have ringed it.
他曾经是一名有一些疯狂的想法的地质学家
He was a geologist once.Had some pretty wild ideas
他对Dalek想干什么有点古怪的猜测
about what the Daleks were up to in that mine.
呃...
Hmm...
这些笔记没什么古怪的
There's nothing wild about these notes.
可以说是很有根据的猜测
A lot of well-informed guesswork I should say.
我们在这挺安全的的
Well, aren't we going to stay here?It'll be safe enough.
我不知道你怎么想的，年轻人
I don't know about you,young man,
我要往贝德福德矿区去的
but I am going to that mine in Bedfordshire.
你，不一定要和我一起去，知道吗？
You er... you don't have to come,you know?
我一向喜欢乡村
I always did prefer the country.
Susan不可能不给我留句话啊
Most unlike Susan not to leave me a message.
我想知道是不是那边出了什么事
I wonder if the Constable's up there?
对不起
Sorry.
不知道它们要把我们带到哪去
I wonder where they're taking us.
我也不知道，我们可能要呆好几天
I don't know,we might be stuck here for days.
等降落时，我们能不能从处理槽那里逃出去？
When we land, I wonder if we could get out of that disposal chute?
我不知道
I don't know.
又一批俘虏
More prisoners.
我们知道你爷爷不在里边
At least we know your grandfather isn't one of them.
-快点，我们得走了 -Susan，进去
- Come on, we'd better be going.- Right, Susan, in you get.
-我来开门 -不，我来
- I'll open the doors.- No, I'll get them.
走吧，我能对付！
Go on!I can manage.
Dortmun!
Dortmun, 回来！
Dortmun, come back!
别傻了！
Don't be a fool!
Dortmun!
看！
Look!
9号巡逻!
Patrol 9 to space ship!
拦住逃跑的人！
Intercept escaping humans.
抓住第九区逃跑的人
Intercept escaping humans travelling in area 9.
寻找他们！
Search for them.
找到叛军了
We have located the rebel machine.
准备消灭他们！
Prepare to annihilate.
那是什么？
What is it?
有个飞碟，他离我们越来越近了！
There's a flying saucer overhead.It's coming closer.
你还好么？
You all right?
还认为你爷爷会跟我们到沃特福德？
You still think this grandfather of yours will follow you to Watford?
我给他留话了，他会去的
If he reads the message I left.
-待会要走很长的路 -我们能行！
- Well, it's a long way on foot.- We'll make it.
我们最好现在走
We'd better get started then.
呃，你说得对
Hmm. You're right.
我们不要进Watford，那里全是Dalek
We'll have to by-pass Watford,the place is full of Daleks.
这条山坡通向Bedfordshire
Bit hilly though,one up to Bedfordshire.
我们必须弄清它们想干什么
We must find out what they're up to.
-还要走多远？-大概三英里
- How far we got to go now?- About three miles.
站住！
Halt!
恩，我说了，大概三英里
As I was saying,about three miles.
-这么近 -嗯
- Everything's still.- Hmm?
我们降落了
The saucer's landed!
跟我来！
Come on!
躲起来
Back!
我不认为我们可以从这里出去！
I don't think we can get out this way.
-那我们总不能呆在这吧！-好吧
- Well, we can't stay in the saucer either.- All right.
我先下
I'll go first.
-怎么样？-没事
- All right? - Yes.
快走
Come on.
-那是什么？-嘘！
- What is it? - Shh!
快走
Come on.
快点！
Move!
在那别动！
Stay where you are!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我们是...
Well, er...
为什么不干活？
Why aren't you on your work detail?
-刚到的？-是的
- Just arrived, haven't you? - Yes.
怪不得你们这么干净
I thought your clothes looked too clean.
你是在那飞船着陆时逃出来的吧
Have you just escaped out of that space ship that just landed?
你们这些傻瓜...
You fools, you haven't a...
来，我来对付他们
Follow me, I'll do the talking.
这两个人在那干什么？
What are these two doing here?
我让他们拿了点工具
I took them out of a work detail to help me collect some tools.
他们没有证件！
They have no identification!
你干了什么？你这个笨蛋
What do you think you're doing,you crazy idiot?
Dalek会发现的，快点弄走他
The Daleks will miss him.We've got to get rid of him.
把他拖到帐篷底下！
Stick him under that tarpaulin.
就这样！
That's it!
把他滚进去
Go on, roll him in.
现在告诉我们可以藏在哪？
Now, come on,show us where we can hide.
工具室！那是你们唯一的机会！
The tool shed over there,that's your only chance.
一会我给你们送点吃的去
I'll send you some food later.
-Boo! -别闹了
- Boo!- Cut that out.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好的，我们不能从这里去Watford。到处都是Dalek
Well, we can't get to Watford that way.The Daleks are everywhere.
-我找不到食物 -别担心
- I couldn't get any food either.- Never mind.
那有个小屋
There's a cottage just over there.
-在哪？-在河对面
- Where?- Across the stream.
-在这里，没人看见你吧？-没有，但外面有人
- 'Ere, nobody saw you did they?- No, but there's someone outside.
让我看一看
Let's take a look.
过来
Come on!
站住！
Stop there!
我们只想找个地方去休息，能给我们一点东西吃吗？
We only want somewhere to rest and a little food, if you've got it.
-你们从哪里来？-伦敦
- Where are you from?- London.
我的朋友腿受伤了
My friend's hurt his leg.
你们要去哪？
Where are you heading?
- Dalek在Bedfordshire的矿井 -不是Watford吗？
- The Daleks' mine in Bedfordshire.- I thought you said Watford.
我爷爷不会呆在那里，那里全是Dalek
Grandfather won't stay there when he finds it's full of Daleks.
我想他会去矿上看看出了什么事
I think he'll go on to the mine.He's bound to be curious.
我们能进去吗？
Can we come in?
算你们走运，现在到处都是巡逻兵
You were lucky to get this far.The patrols are everywhere.
他们日夜不停的巡逻
They never stop, day or night.
是的，我知道
Yes, I know.
还差点抓住我们
They nearly got us.
巡逻的为什么没把你抓走？他们一定知道你在这里
Why haven't the patrols taken you?They must know you're here.
他们当然知道，可我不伤害它们
Oh, they know all right,but we can't harm them.
给俘虏缝衣服
We mend the clothes of the slave workers.
干这个更合适点
We're more useful doing that than working in the mine.
-那你们的食物从哪里来？-它们给我们一些
- Well, how do you manage for food?- They give us some. Not enough.
不过平常都挨饿
Hungry most of the time.
好吧，我们只是稍稍休息一下就够
OK. We'll just rest for a bit,then push on.
给他们喝点汤吧
Give them some of the soup.
你的腿不能再走了
You can't walk on that leg for a while.
你可以留在这里直到你的腿好点
You can stay here till it's better if you like.
谢谢
Thank you.
这里的吃的多半是土豆
Mostly potatoes,but there's a bit of meat in it,
-我得把衣服送去 -你要小心
- I'll have to deliver these clothes.- Mind how you go.
我会注意的
I'll be careful.
你知道我们下了矿井会怎么样吗？
You know what'll happen if we go down into that mine, don't you?
- 再也出不来了 -小伙子
- Chances are we'll never get out again.- My boy...
这个矿是Dalek的活动中心
this mine is the centre of the Dalek activity.
Dortmun在这个问题上有各种理论
Now, Dortmun has various theories on the subject.
没有任何结论，不过他的依据是一样的
None of them conclusive,but all based on one fundamental idea.
它们想要地球里的什么？
They want something that's under the Earth.
是啊，它们要矿产？不可能，你说的
Yes, but what? Minerals?Most unlikely, don't you think?
呃，石油？
Well, oil...
如果我们在Texas或中东，我可能会这么想
If we were in  or the Middle East,I might agree.
但是不
But no...
Dalek有更大的野心，是我们很不理解的原因
No, the Daleks have a far greater reason,a much more alien one.
为了这个目的，它们不惜向我们这个星球开战
Strong enough to make them wage war on this planet.
它们不仅仅是为了征服地球
They are not enslaving Earth merely for conquest.
它们在矿上所做的一切，才是它们的真正目的
What they are doing in this mine is the whole purpose of their invasion.
我们必须知道是什么
We must learn what that is
这样才能找到它们的弱点
if we are to find out where their weakness lies.
-Dalek是没有弱点的 -每个人都有弱点...
- The Daleks have no weakness.- Everybody has a weak...
别想动！
Don't try it!
把你的枪口调过去
Hold the rifle by the barrel.
把它放地上！
Sling it over there.
-这是什么意思？ -闭嘴
- What is the meaning of this? - Shut up!
你们开什么玩笑？
What are you two jokers up to?
听起来你们好像是要到矿里去
Sounded to me as if you wanted to get into the mine.
是的
We do.
可大多数人都想出来
Most people want to get out of it.
那有个麻袋，把它拿过来
There's a sack up there. Get it!
都是食物，我要卖到矿里去
It's full of food.I'm taking it into the mine to sell.
卖吗？
Sell?
我只知道一个去矿里安全的方式
There's only one safe way in and out of the mine and I know it.
如果你真的很想那你可以跟我去
You can go with me if you raelly want
要付路费的
This pays your fare.
除非你想多出钱，那么两个人交一份路费
Two singles, of course.If you want returns that comes higher.
-我们凭什么相信你？ -因为你们不能没有我
- Why should we trust you?- You won't get in without me.
-那为什么你要帮助我们？ -这是生意
- And why are you willing to help us? - It's my line of business.
恩，大家都准备好的时候走
Well, we're ready when you are.
你想找死，还是活得不耐烦了？
Have you got a death wish or something?
我们要在这里呆一晚上，到时候再去矿里
We'll stay here the night and slip into the mine
明天早上走
when the early shift goes on in the morning.
快看！
Look!
一罐饮料
A tin of soup.
还有一罐
Another tin.
白菜
Cabbage.
干得好
You've done well!
我知道他们会给我们更多的食物
I knew they'd give us more food if you told them.
往前走，否则你将被消灭!
Forward, or you will be exterminated.
呃，他们无论如何都要去矿上
Well, they wanted to go to the mine anyway.
我们过不了今晚了，到处都是Dalek
We'll never make it tonight.The place is crawling with Daleks.
我们只需要等待，仅此而已
We'll just have to wait then, that's all.
早上会好点，他们会都去吃早餐
Yeah, might manage it in the morning,while they're having their breakfast.
是啊
Yeah.
呃，闻起来很香啊
Well, that smells good.
是啊
Yes, it does.
-尝尝吧 -哦，谢谢
- Try some?- Oh, thank you.
来吧
Come on.
好了，你们可以走了，他会给你们食物的
All right, you can come out.He's sent you some food.
-恐怕不多，不过也好-谢谢
- Not much I'm afraid, but it is something.- Thanks a lot.
你打算怎么办，不能总呆在这里
What are you going to do?You can't stay here forever.
-Brockley? -谁？
- Brockley?- Who else?
-博士！-Louise!
- Doctor!- Louise!
小点声
Keep your voices down!
-他们是谁？-两个工作爱好者
- Who are those two?- Two work lovers.
他们想产生一个大问题——看起来他们四个是团聚了
They wanted to be in on the big deal.It's quite a reunion.
-你有食物？-最后怎么了？
- Have you got the food?- How about your end?
-我拿到了 -让我们看看
- I've got it.- Let's see it then.
比以前少了
There's not as much as before.
不过，你也可以拿到一点食物，尽管没帮什么忙
Still, you can have the food.I'm doing you a favour though.
那是什么
Is that what it is?
-我想知道这要多少 -这工作快结束了
- How much do you know about this mine?- I know the work's nearly finished.
-你知道它们在干什么？-是的
- Do you know what they're doing?- Yes.
Dalek要提取地球的磁核心
The Daleks are going to extract the metallic core of the Earth.
很疯狂，要用那些东西造个巨大的太空船
Some insane idea of piloting the planet and using it like a giant space ship.
-不可能 -也许吧
- That's impossible!- Maybe.
Dalek声称它们发现了地壳断裂
The Daleks say they've found a fracture in the Earth's crust.
它们的骨头像钻石刀一样
They're going to use that fracture like a diamond cutter would.
还造了一个爆炸装置，下到断层里去
They've set up an explosive device to drop right through the fracture,
要到地球中心
so the metallic core will burst out and plunge towards the sun.
我没敢告诉人们，这整个地区可能被炸得粉碎
I haven't dared to tell the people.This whole area may be blown to atoms.
-可是Dalek准备好了吗 -Dalek会在今天晚上准备好的
- And the Daleks are nearly ready?- They will be ready tonight.
你可以得到一个在矿场的工作？
Could you obtain a plan of the mine workings?
我想我会安排的
I think I might arrange that.
地球的外壳已经被穿透了
The planet's outer core has been penetrated.
炸药已经准备好了
The capsule containing the explosive will now be made ready.
接合电路4
Engage circuit 4.
前置电路4检查现在开始
Pre-circuit 4 check commencing now.
持续最后的检查
Final pre-release check continuing.
爆炸将如期进行
Blast-off will take place as scheduled.
当地球的磁核心被提取
When the Earth's magnetic core is extracted,
我们可以占领它并驾驭这个星球
we can pilot this planet to the vicinity of our own and occupy it.
这是主要的道路
This is obviously the main shaft,bored by the Daleks,
直接通向地壳裂缝
leading straight to the fracture.
在这里，是原来的老矿山竖井
Alongside it here is the original shaft of the old mine
这里的交汇处
which leads to the meeting point
对北极和南极磁场的影响
of the magnetic influence of the North and South Poles.
那这个地方...
That shaft is boarded up now.
是的，是的，是的，但这是我的信念
Yes, yes, yes, but it is my belief
如果我们能以某种方式，把他们的老矿
that if we could somehow deflect their device down the old mine,
的磁力场释放就会有足够的能力
the field of magnetism so released would be powerful enough
吸取Dalek的核心
to suck the Daleks into the very core of the Earth.
-我知道我们可能会使用这个方法 -很好
- I know how we could deflect it.- Good.
Tom，你和他一起去
Tom, you go with him.
我们其余的人，要使某种导流
The rest of us must cause some sort of diversion.
我没有其他人...
I'm not in the rest of us.
不，我不认为你会，这里面，没有我能得到的利润
No, I didn't think you would be.No profit in it, is there?
再见
None. See you.
那么现在你们两个
Now then you two - on your way.
-什么样的分流？-你到时候会知道
- What kind of a diversion? - You'll know when it happens.
好了，快行动吧
And when it does get everybody away from this area as fast as you can.
-祝你好运 -你看怎么办好？
- Good luck.- What do you want us to do?
我要你把Louise带到一个很好的隐藏的地方
I want you to take Louise and find a good hiding place for her.
然后帮助别人离开矿里
Then help get the people away from the mine.
-那你呢？-我呆在这里
- Well, what about you?- I shall stay here
-可是...-我有原因
- But... - I have a reason.
-为什么不让我们都留下？ -不，你该走了
- Why can't we stay here with you?- No, it's time for you to go.
照顾好她
Take care of her.
-我们离它有点近，不是吗？ -是的
- That was a bit close, wasn't it?- Yeah.
不远了
It's not far now.
这里没什么东西
It's deserted here.
过来
Come on.
这里是Dalek 的控制室
The Dalek Control Room's directly above us now.
炸弹就在上面
The bomb's over our heads.
旧的作业坡在哪里？
Where's the old shaft?
-直对着，不是吗？ -也许吧，不然呢？
- Straight up.- It would be, wouldn't it?
好吧，这有一些
It's all right, it's Craddock.
Craddock，帮我们一把
Hey Craddock,come and give us a hand.
快来！
Come on!
走！走！
Go on! Go on!
哦
Oh...
你回来了？
So, you've come back, have you?
听着，我有了一个好主意
Look, I've just had a very good idea to help you.
真的？
Really?
-给你看些东西-是安全的吗？
- I want to show you something.- Is it safe?
当然
Oh, yes, of course.
-我很抱歉 -哦，不要抱歉，我很期待
- I'm so sorry.- Oh, don't apologise. I expected it.
你必须跟我们走
You will come with me.
我说过，他会在这的
I told you he'd be here, didn't I?
-叛军领导人已被抓获。-好
- The rebel leader has been captured.- Excellent.
准备投放爆炸装置
Prepare to position capsule.
装置已进入位置
Capsule to forward position.
爷爷！
Grandfather!
-Susan! -哦,我知道你会找到我
- Susan!- Oh, I knew you'd find me.
在此等候
You two wait with him.
是啊，我还找到了Louise
Yes, and I've found Louise, too.
这是Wyler，就是他在照顾我
This is Mr Wyler he looked after me.
谢谢你，Wyler先生，谢谢
Thank you, Mr Wyler.Thank you.
我真不懂它们为什么要让这些人用双手去挖这么一个矿
Why do they bring up all these people to dig a mine with their bare hands?
要是有个钻头就能节省很多时间
Surely they could use a drill and do the job in halfthe time.
我现在不能解释，但Dortmun是正确的，他们有一个炸弹
I cannot explain that now,but Dortmun was right - they have a bomb.
前进！
Move!
快！
Now!
9号区机器人
Reserve section Robomen 9
到控制中心
will come to Mine Control Centre.
8号，10号区，继续巡逻矿区
Sections 8 and 10 to continue to patrol mine area.
这是叛军首领
This is the rebel leader.
你将被消灭！
You will be exterminated.
我想告诉你一点，你可能感兴趣
You may be interested in something I have discovered.
我知道你们的弱点
I know your weakness!
Dalek没有弱点！
The Daleks have no weakness!
那为什么你们自己不敢挖那个矿？
Then why are you afraid to dig our own mine, hmm?
你们计划把炸弹从作业坡上滑下去
Your bomb is designed to slide down this shaft,
让它冲击地球的裂缝
strike a fracture in the Earth's inner surface
来放出我们这个星球的磁核心
and so release the magnetic core of our planet.
但是裂缝的位置靠近地球两极的交汇点
But the fracture is near the meeting point
所以你们害怕这个磁力
of the magnetic influence of the North and South Poles.
害怕它?不是吗？
You are afraid of that magnetism,are you not?
但是你知道，它对人类没有伤害
But you know that it cannot harm human beings.
但是只要你们犯一个错误，出现了误差，没有把炸弹对准
One mistake, one deviation in the aiming of your bomb,
那么磁核心放出的磁力就可以消灭你们
and enough magnetic energy will be released to destroy you.
我们将不会有任何错误！
There will be no mistake.
什么都无法阻止我们！
Nothing can stop us now.
人类将会被消灭!
The prisoners are to be exterminated.
等等！你们听我说！
One moment -you must listen to me.
如果你们放了我们，我就可以帮助你们
If you spare us, I can help you.
我可以告诉你如何消除这磁力
I can show you how to neutralise this magnetism -
你们的计划就可以安全的继续了
so that your plan can be carried out without danger to yourselves.
9号区机器人来到，停！
Reserve section Robomen 9 as ordered - halt!
快说!
Speak quickly.
-我，呃，告诉你们 -看！
-But I... I'll show you - look!
所有机器人注意！袭击Dalek！
Attention all Robomen -attack the Daleks!
这个命令你们必须服从！
This order cannot be countermanded.
袭击Dalek！
Attack the Daleks!
停下！
Stop him!
停！停！抓住他！
Stop him! Stop him!
消灭!
Exterminate!
注意！机器人的叛变已经失败！
Attention!Robo rebellion has been defeated.'
最后的磁性释放即将进行
Engage final release circuit immediately.
指示器已经指在零
Rebel counter is now set at zero.
紧急情况！俘虏正在逃跑！
Emergency - slaves escaping.
俘虏在逃跑！
'Slaves escaping.'
准备释放爆炸装置
Release the explosive device.
命令所有Dalek镇压叛乱！
Order all Daleks to subdue the rebellion.
Dalek继续控制叛乱
All Daleks proceed to control points.
消灭所有反抗者！
Destroy all resistance.
炸弹准备完毕！
Explosive device is now set.
指针在20时释放
Release will be at 20 Rels.
在50时爆炸！
Explosion will be at 50 Rels.
所有Dalek在指针到40时，跟我去飞船！
Order all Daleks to follow me to space ship at 40 Rels.
爆炸装置错位！
Explosive device is not on course.
在23时即将爆炸！
It will detonate in 23 Rels.
危险！危险！
Danger! Danger!
爆炸偏离位置！
The device has exploded off course.
放弃矿区！
Abandon mine area!
磁力到达危险点！
Magnetic force past danger point.
放弃矿区！
Abandon mine area.
Abandon mine area!
小心！
Look out!
啊，太好了，他起作用了！
Oh, good, it's working!
我们被磁力影响了！
Am affected by magnetic force.
无法控制！无法控制！
Cannot control. Cannot control.
无法控制！
Cannot control.
看！
Look!
它们完了！
That's the finish of that lot anyway.
Dalek们全都完了，Wyler.
The end of all the Daleks who invaded Earth, Wyler.
他们再也不敢来这里了
They'll never dare to land here again.
消灭它们的力量就在脚下
The power to destroy them is at our feet.
强大的，不可抗拒的磁力就来自我们的地球
Strong irresistible magnetic power -from Mother Earth herself.
一切都是相同的,对吗？
Same with everything else, you see?
总是有办法的，只要你仔细想想
There's always an answer to be found,if you only dig deep enough.
-我准备好了，博士-嗯？
- I'm all ready, Doctor.- Hmm?
小伙子，你真了不起，真是警察的荣誉
Oh, yes, yes, splendid, my boy -a credit to the force.
呃，博士，博士
Er... Doctor? Doctor, you er...
博士，你不是答应让我回到抢劫珠宝店的前几分钟吗
Doctor, you did say you'd put me back
强盗抢劫珠宝店的前几分钟，对吗？
a couple of minutes before the villains robbed the jewellery store, didn't you?
我说的，当然
Yes, and so I shall.
Tom，别担心
Don't worry, Tom.
命运在等待你
Your destiny awaits you.
-爷爷，要我打开门吗？-当然，Susan
- Shall I release the doors, Grandfather?- Yes, please, Susie.
-祝你好运！-放心吧！
- Good luck!- Ta!
快走吧！
Let's go. Step on it!
这，这是什么？
'Ere, what's that...
警察 Tom Campbell
Detective Inspector Tom Campbell, OBE.
小伙子们，谢谢了...
Thank you, lads.